export const PHYSICSA2023 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Which of the following statements about the use of simple microscope are true? \nI An upright image is seen \nII The object must be less than one focal length away \nIIl The image is real \nIV The image is magnified",
A: "I, II and IV only",
B: "II and III only",
C: "III and IV only",
D: "I and II only",
answer: "A. I, II, and IV only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. A ball projected into the air at 45° to the horizontal has a range of X. If another ball is projected with the same initial velocity at 75° to the horizontal, its range will be",
A: "equal to X",
B: "less than X.",
C: "greater than X.",
D: "infinite.",
answer: "A. equal to X",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. In the p-type semiconductor, the",
A: "number of holes are equal to the number of electrons.",
B: "electrons are the majority charge carriers.",
C: "holes are the majority charge carriers.",
D: "electrical resistivity is on the increase.",
answer: "C. holes are the majority charge carriers",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Local action is a defect in a voltaic cell in which",
A: "zinc atoms miove into the solution leaving behind electrons.",
B: "hydrogen bubbles form on the copper electrode.",
C: "zinc electrodes dissolve in the electrolyte.",
D: "zinc ions in the solution combine with sulphate ions to form zinc sulphate.",
answer: "A. zinc atoms move into the solution leaving behind electrons",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The efficiency of a machine is always less than 100 % because",
A: "velocity ratio is always less than unity.",
B: "mechanical advantage is always greater than velocity ratio.",
C: "work is done against friction.",
D: "lubrication reduces mechanical advantage.",
answer: "C. work is done against friction",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The half-life of a radioactive substance is 15 minutes. Determine the decay constant.",
A: "3.9 x 10^-4 s^-1",
B: "2.0 x 10^-2 s^-1",
C: "7.7 x 10^-4 s^-1",
D: "4.5 x 10^-2 s^-1",
answer: "C. 7.7 x 10^-4 s^-1",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The gradual reduction in the brightness of an electric bulb connected to a simple voltaic cell when the circuit is switched on is due to",
A: "internal resistance.",
B: "local action.",
C: "thermionic emission.",
D: "polarization.",
answer: "A. internal resistance",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. A litre of hot water at temperature, 0 is added to 3 litres of cold water at a temperature of 30 °C. If the final temperature of the mixture is 50 °C, determine 0.",
A: "110.0 °C",
B: "80.0 °C",
C: "56.7 °C",
D: "150.0 °C",
answer: "B. 80.0 °C",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. An object is placed between two parallel plane mirrors. How many images are formed?",
A: "Infinite",
B: "180",
C: "360",
D: "90",
answer: "A. Infinite",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Which of the following group of materials are all magnetic?",
A: "Iron, lead and brass",
B: "Copper, steel and iron",
C: "Nickel, steel and iron",
D: "Steel, glass and lead",
answer: "C. Nickel, steel, and iron",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. When the temperature of a solid increases, its surface tension",
A: "remains constant.",
B: "increases.",
C: "decreases.",
D: "increases then decreases.",
answer: "C. decreases",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Neutrons are used to initiate fission reactions because they",
A: "have no charge.",
B: "have no mass.",
C: "are not energetic.",
D: "are fast moving.",
answer: "A. have no charge",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. A boat is hit by a wave crest every 5s. If the distance between successive crests is 40 m, determine the speed of the wave.",
A: "8.000 ms^-1",
B: "5.000 m s^-1",
C: "0.100 ms^-1",
D: "0.125 ms^-1",
answer: "B. 5.000 m/s",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The frequency at which capacitive reactance is equal to inductive reactance in an R-L-C series circuit is known as",
A: "threshold frequency.",
B: "maximum frequency.",
C: "critical frequency.",
D: "resonance frequency.",
answer: "D. resonance frequency",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Reverberation results from",
A: "refraction of sound.",
B: "interference of sound.",
C: "reflection of sound.",
D: "diffraction of sound.",
answer: "C. reflection of sound",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The quantity of heat required to raise the temperature of a body by 1 K is called",
A: "specific heat capacity.",
B: "internal energy.",
C: "thermal capacity.",
D: "latent heat of fusion.",
answer: "C. thermal capacity",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. An inflatable ball is projected horizontally with a speed of 5 m s“, from a platform of adjustable height. The distance at which the ball would land from the foot of the platform can be increased by",
A: "increasing the mass of the ball.",
B: "increasing the height of the platform.",
C: "decreasing the speed of projection.",
D: "decreasing the height of the platform.",
answer: "B. increasing the height of the platform",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. An object is placed 20 cm from a converging lens of focal length 15 cm. Determine the image distance",
A: "60 cm",
B: "20 cm",
C: "30cm",
D: "58cm",
answer: "C. 30 cm",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. What is the reactance of a 1F capacitor placed in an a.c circuit of frequency 50 Hz? [x = 3.14] Ol",
A: "2180 Ω",
B: "2000 Ω",
C: "6342 Ω",
D: "3485 Ω",
answer: "A. 2180 Ω",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. A man on a 40.0 m high building drops a stone of mass 5.0 kg. Determine the kinetic energy of the stone midway through its fall. ' [g=10m s?]",
A: "0.1 J",
B: "10.0 J",
C: "100.0 J",
D: "1000.0 J",
answer: "C. 100.0 J",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. An object is moved from the earth to the moon. Which of the following quai ities remain constant?",
A: "Acceleration",
B: "Energy",
C: "Mass",
D: "Weight",
answer: "C. Mass",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. An alternating current with a peak value of 5 A passes through a resistor of resistance 10 Ω. Determine the rate at which energy is dissipated in the resistor.",
A: "125.0 W",
B: "250.0 W",
C: "35.4 W",
D: "50.0 W",
answer: "B. 250.0 W",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The distance between two consecutive nodes of a stationary wave is",
A: "λ",
B: "λ/2",
C: "λ/3",
D: "λ/4",
answer: "B. λ/2",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. A current of 6 A passed through a wire in 2 minutes. How many electrons were transferred in this time? [e = 1.6 x 107 9c]",
A: "9.4 x 10^20",
B: "4.5 x 10^21",
C: "1.3 x 10^13",
D: "1.9 x 10^20",
answer: "B. 4.5 x 10^21",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Electromagnetic radiations can be classified based on their",
A: "amplitudes and wavelengths. .",
B: "wavelengths and frequencies.",
C: "velocities and frequencies.",
D: "velocities and amplitudes.",
answer: "B. wavelengths and frequencies",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. A projectile is fired from ground level with a speed of 500 m s”! at'30° to the horizontal. Determine the range. [ g=10 ms}",
A: "433013m",
B: "21650.6m",
C: "12500.0 m",
D: "43.3m",
answer: "B. 21650.6 m",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. A satellite moves with escape velocity, v, around the earth of radius ,r. Which of the following equations is correct? [ g = acceleration due to gravity]",
A: "v= √2r",
B: "v= √2gr",
C: "v= √2g / r",
D: "v= √2r / g",
answer: "B. v = √2gr",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. A glider of mass 0.20 kg on an air track is moving at 3.6 m s-' towards a second glider of mass 0.25 kg, which is moving at 2.0 m s~ in the opposite direction. When the two gliders collide, they stick together. Determine their common speed.",
A: "0.49 ms!",
B: "0.12ms!",
C: "41.10ms7",
D: "23.40ms'!",
answer: "A. 0.49 m/s",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The equivalent unit of moment of a force is",
A: "kgm s^-2",
B: "kgm s^-1",
C: "kg m^2 s^-1",
D: "kg m^2 s^-2",
answer: "C. kg m² s⁻¹",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. A wire is moved across a magnetic field. The emf ponies in the wire depends on the following factors except the",
A: "orientation of the wire with respect to the staanette field vector.",
B: "durability of the wire.",
C: "magnetic flux density of the field.",
D: "length of the wire.",
answer: "B. durability of the wire",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The S.I unit of thermal conductivity is",
A: "W m^-2 K^-1.",
B: "W m^2 K^-1.",
C: "W m K^-1.",
D: "W m^-1 K^-1",
answer: "D. W m⁻¹ K⁻¹",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Fleming’s Right Hand rule is used to determine the",
A: "direction of the force on a charged particle moving perpendicularly to a magnetic field.",
B: "direction of the force on a current carrying conductor in a magnetic field.",
C: "direction of an induced current in a straight conductor moving in a magnetic field.",
D: "magnetic field direction around a current-carrying straight conductor.",
answer: "C. direction of an induced current in a straight conductor moving in a magnetic field",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following units represents Young’s modulus of elasticity?",
A: "kg m^-2 s^-2",
B: "kg m^-3 s^-1",
C: "kg m^-1 s^-1",
D: "kg m^-1 s^-2",
answer: "D. kg m⁻¹ s⁻²",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. An image which cannot be formed on a screen is said to be ~",
A: "inverted.",
B: "magnified.",
C: "real.",
D: "virtual",
answer: "D. virtual",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Which of the following quantities are scalar?  \nI   Force  \nII  Electric potential \nIII Kinetic energy  \nIV  Momentum",
A: "II and III only",
B: "I and IV only",
C: "II, III and IV only",
D: "I, II and III only",
answer: "A. II and III only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The process in which two light atomic nuclei combine to form a heavy nuclide with the release of energy is",
A: "chain reaction.",
B: "nuclear fission.",
C: "nuclear fusion.",
D: "radioactivity.",
answer: "C. nuclear fusion",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The vacuum in a thermos flask reduces heat loss by",
A: "convection and radiation only.",
B: "conduction, convection and radiation.",
C: "conduction and convection only.",
D: "conduction and radiation only.",
answer: "B. conduction, convection, and radiation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. A bullet embedded in a patient’s leg can be examined using",
A: "λ - rays.",
B: "β - particles.",
C: "α - particles.",
D: "X - rays.",
answer: "D. X-rays",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. A 600 W electric heater is used to raise 0.7 kg of water from 15 °C to 55 °C. Determine the time involved in the process. [Specific heat capacity of water = 4200 J k ]",
A: "90s",
B: "196s",
C: "691s",
D: "516s",
answer: "B. 196s",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. As an object in an elliptical orbit moves closer to the sun, its orbital velocity",
A: "decreases.",
B: "increases.",
C: "varies randomly.",
D: "remains unchanged.",
answer: "B. increases",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. A student of mass 40 kg climbs a stair-case of 20 steps, each of height, 15 cm in 2 seconds. Determine the work done by the student against gravity. [g=10m 37]",
A: "12000 J",
B: "1200 J",
C: "1000 J",
D: "100 J",
answer: "B. 1200 J",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Which of the following factors does not affect the viscosity of a fluid?",
A: "Colour",
B: "Temperature",
C: "Pressure",
D: "Concentration",
answer: "A. Colour",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The work done to move a unit positive charge from infinity to a point in an electric field is",
A: "electric potential.",
B: "electric force.",
C: "electric power.",
D: "electric field intensity.",
answer: "A. electric potential",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. A 1200 W electric iron draws power from a 240 V mains supply. If it is to be protected with a fuse, what would be the most suitable current of the fuse?",
A: "12.0A",
B: "0.2A",
C: "5.0A",
D: "8.0A",
answer: "C. 5.0 A",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The universal gravitational constant, G, differs from acceleration due to gravity ,g, in that",
A: "G is a vector quantity while g is a scalar quantity.",
B: "G veries throughout the universe while g is constant everywhere.",
C: "g is measured in N kg! while G is measured in N m? kg~.",
D: "g has dimensions-LT ? while G is dimensionless.",
answer: "C. g is measured in N kg⁻¹ while G is measured in N m² kg⁻²",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Which of the following particles does not experience electrostatic force?",
A: "β - particle .",
B: "Electron",
C: "Neutron",
D: "Proton",
answer: "C. Neutron",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. A note is the octave of another note if one of the notes is",
A: "twice the frequency of the other.",
B: "twice the amplitude of the other.",
C: "eight times the frequency of the other.",
D: "eight times the amplitude of the other.",
answer: "A. twice the frequency of the other",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. In the clinical thermometer, the function of the constriction is to \nI prevent the back flow of the mercury after use. \nII ensure the back flow of mercury after use. \nIII maintain the thermometric property of mercury. \nIV allow the temperature attained to be read. Which of the statements above are correct? SBD",
A: "Il and IV only",
B: "I and IV only",
C: "I and III only",
D: "I, II and IV only",
answer: "C. I and III only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. A speed of 72 km h7! is equivalent to OE",
A: "60 ms^-1",
B: "30 ms^-1",
C: "20 ms^-1",
D: "10 ms^-1",
answer: "B. 30 m/s",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The image formed by a convex lens is erect and magnified four times. If the focal length of the lens is 20 cm, determine the object distance.",
A: "20 cm",
B: "30 cm",
C: "10 cm",
D: "15 cm",
answer: "B. 30 cm",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]